Hello, you are welcome to the next episode of Sharma ji's Hindi mein,
today we are going to learn a very
important concept that of conjunction in German,
conjunctions which in Hindi are called conjunctions
which join two or more
words or sentences and
this is very important friends,
first of all we learned the alphabets,
after that we made words from them,
words we made sentences, sentences,
now you are going to join these sentences, so from this
you get kilo based on the idea, that is
I play cricket, I
like cricket, I play cricket
because I like cricket, which is
because or and or friend, these are all
conjunctions in English, there will be ad and
but etc. So today we will
learn the most important 6 conjunctions, there are
many such conjunctions in any language,
see in Hindi also there is only but, it also has
but-but, how many can there be, these are the
most important, we are going to watch, so let's start, first of all
these three are the easiest, the best
food order, meaning and so  We all know that
in numbers, okay, order means and and and our means
but you mean but these three are
very simple, what to do is put two sentences
in the middle, put custom, your
sentence is ready, hybrid and you
drink Pepsi, this trick, Kundur
printhead, C cutter, just put them in the middle,
no, I can play cricket and
decentralized Harry Potter again, play cricket
and we can read Harry Potter, this is why cricket
is pillar,
ka powder and VM them doctor has
last, I like it, butta plates, his
left buttock, tennis, this mask, cricket marks, like you can still be alive,
his starts,
this mask request, this pillar on the side,
this pillar tennis, nothing, look,
if you go and look from above, then only those
fairness in the middle, accidents, sentence,
you are done, you got 3 conjunctions, i10,
i20, JNU, weight worker, species of Urdu, on
this, if there is nothing on team WhatsApp,
three conjunctions started coming, the second type is
very important, friends, because
if you like this  If you understand then you will
understand many advances in German about fasting, so
what happens in it, so basically
where does it go, in the world it is
called fasting, Pawar
's proposal in board class English,
not vomiting, stomach cleansing comes with them, so
these are specially seen under category-3,
which intercourse, wild wild means death,
valve means forests and
value means young women and conditioner, so
understand what happens in these, if you understand this then you have
many proper
concepts, you have to understand what happens in these,
this after boiled, this vaidya, the sentence
after boil or the
word that is running in the channel, the word that is run
or conjugate in it, upper class Gujjars, the
second is strong, pick it up and take it to the end,
pick it up tomorrow morning, take it to the end, if
you understand this concept then your question is what to do, from the
sentence that is going after file on wall van,
you have to pick up the work of the second position
or the work that is running
and middle, David Thoreau passes the exam  If
you will understand then this itself is a
drink it because while it is
requested to sell it with sentences
different what is this trick hour ismart
that when we will add from there this love doing
boil second position path will go in the end
and Ishte Mang was a simple way
so second position power
running class is the admin of the group
similarly identity one so alive coffee
liking rice this trick day this mask
on this trick you do boond ishq on mother ke
prasad labour leader bana to dharma hota
100 08:21 MLA
A string doing this week sprinkler
tag venish chilli yes now a simple second
position cover running group's admin
that try some three sentences with me then
you will face some problems you can also
make it with me so first of all say ah yes
play cricket because it is live cricket
IPL cricket because the like then what will happen
is pillar cricket wild this cricket mang
IPL cricket team andher football cricket
life light bill spinner cricket Woolwich
flower on Balma  You can play cricket then I play
football with that ball a flu football ishq
love kush double way this line thal hobbs time
simple note as per there
is nothing hard in it now I am going to tell you this small thing
due to which people get confused
understand the rules which have been made roles the rule is
any first judgment royal came so from which the work
going on this question should be taken up by the admiral
these people do not understand it properly then get confused and write
two sentences
hello hi dad i like cricket because it can cricket
live cricket because they can
play cricket i like it is this mask
request i can play cricket star
cricket club so what will you do by joining
second position what is champion by taking up work
and middle legs harassment ke paas kar gaya hai
your what are you doing russian na first
in its length body mind in sentence because
he feels scared attainment that sentence from has
caught and some second position is for advance
so what will happen in this great cricketer
ishq cricket yellow color ka in simple and
construction hi understand then there is nothing hard
and
good type of or  Identification must
drink, drink water must read team
sprint cut, while adding state wrinkle in this it will
go in mosted, this trick is done by
wire State Bank Anmol, there is nothing like that
if this concept is clear to you brothers and
sisters, then there are many other
connectors like waste is Varun means
during fall means these or today means
I was 46 years old, I did this etc., nothing like this,
take the same 2 sentences and
join them, bronze medal is the only thing to be done,
indirect speech is scheduled, all this
also works in the same way, but we will do this when
we take advanced connectors, Musammi also, this to be one
's Dongri, then we will
see, read it is from the basic concept, the second one
with its skin, after these the word
Vargis, the sentence which is going to come,
catch the young man who is walking in it, take the dates,
all of them will understand the concept, then they do
not have to do anything equally, there is
Anukul, I am the Admiral of Varuna,
now what I am saying in the next 2 minutes, if you do
not understand then it will be fine, I am just giving
Quizjas Kawardha Concept Okay, so
sometimes you can bring this essay forward in German, that right
there in this tag mark Priyanka situated
Wild Steve Martin's stay,
how is it now, what did you do in it,
first you brought the barren forward, then it was ahead, that is why it happened
in the condition and then it came, there is
no need for you to understand all this, so
for us it is not on the doorstep
because I like tea, I drink tea,
this is not very very logical and I did
not make any such compulsion in this trust,
you have to learn from this also, so special, I will
say in 1821, it is not needed for life also, if
someone said that then you
should know how it can come first, then
this snap results can come first, then
hotspots, you will have to play over again, did not worth
putting this in 2 minutes, I
understood it only, it is fine even if I forgot, okay, so
again we can come back to our important,
see what did you learn today, we learned
conjunction, learned to join two sentences,
first of all we said kund order, very
simple  Catch some sentences, add absent
and then we do the not important function like this, this
world and way goes and which ones are while van
and tell what is happening, the
second to catch which is after that, the one who catches it from the sentence, the
admin of the group will
take it, Dixit and later we said
that if this concept is clear to you, then there are
many such characters which
we will see whenever I see it in advance connect,
I hope that you all have understood this connect,
we will meet in the next class,
thank you.